[
    {
        "front": "regular imperfect -ar endings",
        "back": "-aba, -abas, -aba, -ábamos, -abais, -aban",
		"examples":[
			"¿De qué hablabais? / What did you all talk about?",
			"¿De qué hablabais Roberto y tú ayer por la noche? / What did you and Roberto talk about last night?",
			"Hablábamos con frecuencia de nuestro futuro. / We would often talk about our future."
		]
    },
    {
        "front": "regular imperfect -er/-ir endings",
        "back": "-ía, -ías, -ía, -íamos, -íais, -ían"
    },
    {
        "front": "regular preterite -ar endings",
        "back": "-é, -aste, -ó, -amos, -asteis, -aron"
    },
    {
        "front": "regular preterite -er/-ir endings",
        "back": "-í, -iste, -ió, -imos, -isteis, -ieron"
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular preterite: ser",
        "back": "fui, fuiste, fue, fuimos, fuisteis, fueron",
        "notes": ["no accents as with preterite ir, dar and ver"]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular preterite: ir",
        "back": "fui, fuiste, fue, fuimos, fuisteis, fueron",
        "examples": [
            "¿Adónde fuisteis? / Where did you go?",
            "¿Por qué no fuisteis? / Why didn't you go?"
        ]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular preterite: dar",
        "back": "di, diste, dio, dimos, disteis, dieron",
        "examples": [
            "Dio el primer paso. / He made the first move.",
            "¿Quién te dio eso? / Who gave you this?",
            "Le dimos una manzana. / We gave him an apple.",
            "Los dimos la mano. / We shook hands.",
            "¿Le diste la llave? / Did you give the key to him?"
        ],
        "notes": ["parallel to ver: vi, viste, vio, vimos, visteis, vieron"]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular preterite: ver",
        "back": "vi, viste, vio, vimos, visteis, vieron",
        "notes": ["parallel to dar: di, diste, dio, dimos, disteis, dieron"]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular imperfect: ir",
        "back": "iba, ibas, iba, íbamos, ibais, iban",
        "notes": ["1x accent in nosotros as with ser"],
		"examples":[
			"Pensé que íbamos a ganar. / I thought we were going to win.",
			"César y yo íbamos a menudo  / César and I would often go to the movies."
		]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular imperfect: ser",
        "back": "era, eras, era, éramos, erais, eran",
        "notes": ["1x accent in nosotros as with ir"]
    },
    {
        "front": "irregular imperfect: ver",
        "back": "veía, veías, veía, veíamos, veíais, veían",
        "notes": ["6x accents", "[BAY-ya]"],
        "examples": [
            "Me veían. / They saw me.",
            "Ambos se veían sospechosos. / Both of them seem suspicious."
        ]
    }
]
